Steve Coffey

stevendcoffey@gmail.com · +1 (810) 569-4845 · GitHub · Linkedin · stevendcoffey.com

Summary

I'm a founder and full-stack engineer with a decade of experience building for web and mobile. As a co-founder of AssetClass, I built four greenfield products spanning AI, fintech, and travel. At Sonder, I increased repeat bookings by 10% and elevated operational efficiency by 15% through the development of our mobile app and guest messaging platform.

Work Experience

AssetClass

Co-Founder, Head of Engineering • Sept. 2021 - Sept. 2023

- Built and launched four products based on successive waves of market ideation and user feedback:
 - AssetClass: a modern digital wealth advisor, helping investors track assets across multiple accounts. Grew to 1500 users.
 - · Factor.fyi: a programmable dashboard enabling investors and researchers to query the world's financial data with SQL.
 - Yuzu: A high-performance financial data API that allowed fintech developers to easily build on vast financial datasets with a GraphQL, WebSocket, and SQL APIs.
 - **Trava:** An Al-driven travel advisor, streamlining planning and booking for intricate journeys, including unfamiliar destinations and multi-city stops.

Sonder

Staff Software Engineer, Tech Lead • June 2018 - Sept. 2021

- Drove the API design and mobile development for Sonder's iOS and Android apps. The mobile app improved our customer satisfaction score, led to a 10% increase in repeat bookings, and became a cornerstone of the company's public markets debut.
- Led the system architecture and roll-out of Sonder's guest messaging platform, in coordination with a cross-functional group of
 product and operational stakeholders, yielding a 15% reduction in handle time of guest communications.
- Directed a mentorship program for 20+ engineers, blending talks on new technologies with live demos to elevate their expertise.

Braintree

Software Engineer • July 2015 - June 2018

- Owned Android and iOS SDKs used by 8.3 million customers daily. SDK adoption drove significant increases in YoY transaction volume.
- Developed and scaled an analytics service for client SDK metrics, handling 1.1k requests/second.
- Built a tool to auto-generates server SDKs from OpenAPI schema, resulting in a 40% reduction in developer maintenance time.

Barracuda Networks

Software Engineer, Mobile Team Lead • Oct. 2013 - June 2015

- Led the mobile team for Copy, a cloud-storage platform with 5M+ users, overseeing four developers across iOS and Android.
- Implemented a shared C++ library, cutting over 20k lines of redundant platform-specific code for data sync and storage.
- Established and evangelized a unified design language for Barracuda's Android apps, ensuring consistency across the product line.

Skills & Proficiencies

Expert:	Ruby/Rails	Python	React/Preact	Typescript	Node.js	Postgres	Golang	React Native	CSS	GraphQL
Advance	ed: Swift,	Objective-C	Java Kotlin	Docker	AWS					
Familiar: C++ Rust Flask Web Components (Lit)										

Education

University of Michigan, Class of 2013

B.A., Screen Arts & Cultures